Guide to the Francis Warrington Dawson Family Papers, 1386-1963, bulk 1859-1950 RL.10147
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Francis Warrington Dawson family papers
1386-1963, bulk 1859-1950
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Dawson, Francis Warrington, 1840-1889
RL.10147
30 Linear Feet 7,986 items
Journalist, of Charleston, S.C., and Versailles, France. The collection contains the papers of Francis Warrington Dawson, who was born Austin John Reeks; his wife, Sarah Ida Fowler Morgan Dawson; and their son, Francis Warrington Dawson II, better known as Warrington Dawson. The papers are primarily literary in character but also include many letters. Francis's papers are primarily autobiographical with information about his Civil War service, travels, courtship, and career. Also present are Morgan family papers describing social life in New Orleans and Baton Rouge, La., in the second half of the 19th century, especially during Reconstruction. Warrington Dawson materials document his work with the American Embassy in Paris and describes French life and politics. Also present is material from his work as director of French Research for Colonial Williamsburg, Inc., including copies (made from the originals at Colonial Williamsburg) of original documents pertaining to French participation in the American Revolution. Also included are copies of 18th century maps of North America, Williamsburg, Va., and positions of the French and American armies in New York and Virginia during the Revolutionary War.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Francis Warrington Dawson Family Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift between 1950 and 1988.
Historical note
Francis Warrington (Frank or F.W.) Dawson was born as Austin John Reeks in London in 1841. He changed his name when he left England for the Confederacy in 1862. During the Civil War he served in the Confederate navy and the cavalry, fighting at Gettysburg and eventually earning a promotion to captain under General James Longstreet. Following the end of the Civil War, Frank Dawson settled in Charleston, South Carolina, and became the editor of the News and Courier.
Frank married Sarah Fowler Morgan in 1874. Sarah Morgan was born in New Orleans, Louisiana, and moved with her family to Baton Rouge as a child. She kept a diary of her Civil War experiences from 1862 through April 1865, which was later edited into A Confederate Girl's Diary and published by her children in 1913. Following her marriage to Frank Dawson, the couple had three children, including Francis Warrington Dawson II, known as Warrington, born in 1878. Warrington Dawson was a newsman, novelist, editor, special assistant to the American Embassy in Paris, and director of French research for Colonial Williamsburg. Warrington befriended several notable persons, including Theodore Roosevelt and Joseph Conrad. He accompanied Roosevelt on his African safari in 1909.
Frank Dawson the elder was murdered by Charleston doctor Thomas McDow in 1889 while the two argued over a French-Swiss maid employed by the Dawsons. Once widowed, Sarah Dawson moved to live with her son, Warrington, in France. She died in 1909.
Warrington Dawson's letters with Joseph Conrad became the focus of a book by Duke University professor Dale B.J. Randall, which led Dawson to give the family's papers to the university's special collections in the 1950s.
Collection Overview
The collection comprises the papers of Francis Warrington (Frank) Dawson (1840-1889), whose original name was Austin John Reeks; his wife, Sarah Ida Fowler (Morgan) Dawson; and of their son, Francis Warrington Dawson II, known as Warrington Dawson (1878-1962). The papers are primarily literary in character, with many editorials, newspaper writings, short stories, novels, articles, scrapbooks, diaries, reminiscences, and letters.
There are several series in the collection: Correspondence, Photographs, Scrapbooks, Writings, and Printed Materials document the family's activities in the late nineteenth through mid-twentieth centuries. Warrington Dawson's research interests in French manuscripts, early American history, and family genealogy are also documented in the French Manuscripts and Research Files series.
Baton Rouge (La.) -- Social life and customs; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Personal narratives, Confederate; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Participation, French; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783 -- Sources; France -- Social life and customs -- 20th century; Dramatists; Diplomatic and consular service, American -- France; Charleston earthquake, S.C., 1886 -- Pictorial works; New Orleans (La.) -- Social life and customs; Maps; Louisiana -- Social life and customs; Journalists -- Correspondence; Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877) -- Louisiana; North America -- Maps; New York (State) -- Maps; Williamsburg (Va.) -- Maps; Virginia -- Maps; Charleston News and Courier; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919; Dawson, Warrington, 1878-1962; Dawson, Sarah Morgan, 1842-1909; Morgan, Howell; Morgan family; Conrad, Joseph, 1857-1924; Colonial Williamsburg Foundation -- Employees; Dawson, Francis Warrington, 1840-1889; Dawson, Francis Warrington, 1840-1889
- Correspondence, 1859-1963 and undated
  Scope and Contents
  The Correspondence series has been arranged alphabetically by correspondent, with general correspondence arranged chronologically at the end of the series. The series also includes Warrington Dawson's diplomatic dispatches and assorted diplomatic papers from Alphonse Pageot.
  Morgan family correspondence, beginning in 1859, describes the social life and customs in Baton Rouge and New Orleans, Louisiana; in Paris, France; and the death of Henry Waller Morgan in a duel in 1861. Letters of Thomas Gibbes Morgan, Sr., describe Confederate mobilization in 1861. Correspondence of Frank Dawson and members of the Morgan family describe Dawson's passage on the blockade runner Nashville, his career as ordnance officer in Longstreet's corps and later in Fitzhugh Lee's cavalry corps; the destruction of homes in Louisiana by the war and Butler's conduct in New Orleans; the battle of Fredericksburg; imprisonment at Fort Delaware; refugee life at Macon, Mississippi; cavalry operations; the causes of Confederate defeat; a duel of Henry Rives Pollard, editor of the Richmond Examiner; politics and journalism in Reconstruction South Carolina; the editorial policies of Dawson's paper, the Charleston News and Courier; accusations of bribery, fraud, and libel; the courtship of Dawson and Sarah (Morgan) Dawson; Dawson's refusal of a challenge to a duel by Martin Witherspoon Gary; the army bill, 1879; the Tilden-Hayes disputed election, 1876; the redemption of South Carolina; Morgan family genealogy; travel in Italy and Europe in the 1880s; education in South Carolina at state-supported colleges and the Citadel; the Charleston earthquake, 1886; Dawson's alleged remarks about Grover Cleveland, reported in the New York World, 1886; labor and labor organizations; the tariff; court procedures in South Carolina; Confederate veterans' organizations; Democratic Party affairs; Dawson's debts; his murder; and the settlement of his estate. Among Dawson's frequent correspondents are Daniel Henry Chamberlain, Edward B. Dickinson, Samuel Dibble, Fitzhugh Lee, Robert Baker Pegram, Henry A. M. Smith, Hugh Smith Thompson, Benjamin Ryan Tillman, Giddings Whitney, and Benjamin H. Wilson.
  There is also correspondence of Sarah Dawson and Warrington Dawson, newsman, novelist, editor, special assistant to the American Embassy in Paris, and director of French research for Colonial Williamsburg. This material gives glimpses of French life, 1900-1950, and information on the families of Joseph Conrad and Theodore Roosevelt. Regular letters of Sarah Dawson to Eunice (Martin) Dunkin (Mrs. William Huger Dunkin) and to her sister, Mrs. Lavina (Morgan) Drum of Bethesda, Maryland, comment on French and Washington, D.C., social life and customs. Dawson's writings as Paris correspondent of the United Press Associations of America after 1900 are in clippings in the scrapbooks. They reflect French and world affairs. Topics treated in correspondence include Theodore Roosevelt's safari; Roosevelt's opinions; press relations for the Roosevelt party in Africa; Roosevelt's reviews of Dawson's books; Dawson's lectures and writings; Conrad's writings; other literary matters; John Powell's career as a concert pianist; seances and mediums; the Taft administration; Roosevelt and race relations; the Negro in Liberia, Nigeria, Haiti, and the U.S.; Roosevelt's political career; the Fresh Air Art Society of London; the organization of the press bureau in the U.S. embassy in Paris; and the work of the Foreign Department of the Committee on Public Information.
  Warrington Dawson's correspondence also covers German reparations; relief work in Austria and the Near East; details of embassy staff work; George Harvey's mission to Europe, 1921; the Washington Disarmament Conference; French finance and politics; war debts; international finance; Coueism; French socialism; a crisis in the publication of the Charleston News and Courier, 1927; the boy scout movement; the Conrad family after Joseph's death; Theodore Roosevelt; U.S. investment in the U.S.S.R.; the restoration of Colonial Williamsburg, Virginia; the French dead at Yorktown; research in French sources on Rochambeau's army; reports to Harold Shurtleff, in charge of the research department of Colonial Williamsburg; the research of Peter Stuyvesant Barry on his grandfather, Frank Dawson; personal and family matters; Dawson's health; restoration of the Lee mansion, Stratford; the Great Depression in the United States and in France; the genealogy of the Chambrun family; the role of Lafayette in Florida land settlement; the Compañía Arrendataria del Monopolio de Petroleos, a Spanish firm in which the French Petroleum Company held an interest; the war records of Theodore Roosevelt's sons; and autograph collecting for the Schroeder Foundation, Webster Groves, Missouri. Major correspondents of Warrington Dawson include Ethel (Dawson) Barry, Phyllis (Windsor-Clive) Benton, Jessie Conrad, Joseph Conrad, Annie Cothran, Alice Dukes, Camille Flammarion, Clarence Payne Franklin, A. H. Frazier, Hugh Gibson, Alice Stopford Green, Yves Guyot, Mary Goodwin, William Archer Rutherfoord Godwin, Herman Hagedorn, Ralph Tracy Hale, Constance (Cary) Harrison, Leland Harrison, Elizabeth Hayes, Henriette Joffre, James Kerney, Grace King, Rudyard Kipling, Georges Ladoux, William Loeb, Jr., Samuel Frank Logan, Andrew W. Miller, C. V. Miller, Francois Millet, L. D. Morel, James Morris Morgan, Frederick Palmer, John Powell, Auguste Rodin, the Duke end Duchess de Rohan, Edith Roosevelt, Nicholas Roosevelt, Theodore Roosevelt, Max Savelle, H. L. Schroeder, George Sharp, Hallie (Clough) Sharp, Philip Simms, George E. Smith, Vance Thompson, and Robert William Vail.
  - Abadie-Duqué, F. to Dawson, Warrington, 1925 (Box 1)
  - Abadie-Duqué, F. to [?], 1918-1944 and undated (Box 1)
  - Abbott, Lawrence to Dawson, Warrington, 1909-1922 (Box 1)
  - Adams, H.W. to Dawson, Warrington, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Horace (Mrs.) to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Adams, John Quincy to Nelson, Hugh, 1823 (Box 1)
  - Alber, Grace to Dawson, Warrington, undated (Box 1)
  - Aldrich, Alfred to Dawson, F. W., 1888 (Box 1)
  - Aldrich, Alfred to Morgan, Sarah, 1891 (Box 1)
  - Aldrich, James to Dawson, F. W., 1888 (Box 1)
  - Aldrich, James to [?], 1889 (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Eliza to Morgan, Sarah, 1889 (Box 1)
  - Alexander, E. P. to Dawson, F. W., 1887 (Box 1)
  - Alexander, E. P. to Morgan, Sarah, 1889 (Box 1)
  - Algoud, Maurice to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Allen, B. L. to Dawson, Warrington, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Allison, R. E. to [?], 1889 (Box 1)
  - Allport, F. W. to Dawson, Warrington, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Almeida, Armando to Dawson, Warrington, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Amader, R. A. to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 1)
  - American Society of the French Legion of Honor to [?], 1932 (Box 1)
  - Ancel, A. F. to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, J. to Dawson, Ethel, 1889 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Joseph to Nelson, Hugh, 1823 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Warwick to [?], 1934 (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Alice to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Angier, F. W. to Dawson, F. W., 1887 (Box 1)
  - Appell, Amélie to Dawson, Warrington, 1929 (Box 1)
  - Appleton, John to Appleton, Thomas, 1824 (Box 1)
  - Archambault, G. to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Arend, F. van den to Butcher, Henry, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Arlson, Harry Leon to Dawson, Warrington, 1911 (Box 1)
  - Armes, Ethel to Dawson, Warrington, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Armour, Norman to various, 1930-1931 (Box 1)
  - Armour, Norman to Dawson, Warrington, 1928-1947 (Box 1)
  - Arnoux, Guy to Dawson, Warrington, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Ashley, C. S. to [?], 1888 (Box 1)
  - Atwood, Herman to Dawson, F. W., 1888 (Box 1)
  - Aubert, Jacque to Dawson, Warrington, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Auerbach, Frederice to Dawson, Warrington, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Auerbach, Joan to Dawson, Warrington, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Auld, Donald to various, 1888 (Box 1)
  - Aupied, Ch. To [?], 1932 (Box 1)
  - Austen, David to Dawson, F. W., 1887-1889 (Box 1)
  - Austin, O. P. to Dawson, Warrington, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Auziere, M. To Dawson, Warrington, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Azan, G. Paul to Dawson, Warrington, 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - Azzoni, Armando to Dawson, Warrington, 1922 (Box 1)
  - Bac, Ferdinand to [?], 1911-1913 (Box 1)
  - Bache, René to [?], 1888 (Box 1)
  - Bacheller & Co. to [?], 1888 (Box 1)
  - Bacon, John to Dawson, F. W., 1887-1888 (Box 1)
  - Bacon, Robert to Briand, M., 1910 (Box 1)
  - Badeau, Adam to [?], 1888 (Box 1)
  - Badham, Henry to stockholders, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Bagby, Paula to Morgan, Sarah, 1889-1890s (Box 1)
  - Bailey, Elizabeth to Morgan, Sarah, 1889 (Box 1)
  - Bainier, Jacques to [?], 1921 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Mary to Dawson, Warrington, 1931? (Box 1)
  - Baker, Newton to Dawson, Warrington, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Ray to Dawson, Warrington, 1909 (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Briscoe to Dawson, F. W., 1861-1865 (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, J. to Dawson, Warrington, 1930-1932 (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Runyon to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Balme, J. M. de la to [?], 1935 (Box 1)
  - Balthazard, M. to [?], 1932 (Box 1)
  - Banigan, Maurice to Dawson, Warrington, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Bapuereau, Elizabeth to [?], 1907 (Box 1)
  - Bardin, James to General Ford, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Barley, Margie to [?], 1889 (Box 1)
  - Barnard, C. to Dawson, Warrington, 1912 (Box 1)
  - Barnard, G. Inman to Dawson, Warrington, 1925-1930 (Box 1)
  - Barnes, W. H. to [?], 1914 (Box 1)
  - Barneville, F. to Dawson, Warrington, 1927-1930 (Box 1)
  - Barneville, M. F. to Dawson, Warrington, 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - Barnum, William to Dawson, F. W., 1888 (Box 1)
  - Barnwell, J. W. to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Barnwell, Nathaniel to Dawson, Warrington, 1930-1946 (Box 1)
  - Baroncelli, E. F. de to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Barrière, Emile to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Barry, André to Dawson, Warrington, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Barry, Ethel to Dr. Ball, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Barry, Ethel to Dawson, Warrington, 1906-1947 and undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Barry, Ethel to [?], 1917-1924 (Box 2)
  - Barry, Herbert to various, 1905-1944 (Box 2)
  - Barry, Herbert to Dawson, Warrington, 1905-1946; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Barry, J. Nelson to [?], 1928 (Box 2)
  - Barry, Stuyvesant to various, 1930-1954 (Box 2)
  - Barry, Stuyvesant to Dawson, Warrington, 1924-1954 (Box 2)
  - Bartlett, Frederich to Dawson, Warrington, 1914 (Box 2)
  - Baschet, Marcel to Dawson, Warrington, 1900 (Box 2)
  - Batcheller, Bates to Dawson, Warrington, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Batcheller, Tryphosa to Dawson, Warrington, 1931-1939 (Box 2)
  - Bates, J. H. to Mr. Riordan, 1895 (Box 2)
  - Bates, W. J. to Morgan, Sarah, 1891 (Box 2)
  - Baynard, Henry to Morgan, Sarah, 1889 (Box 2)
  - Baynard, Henry to Dawson, Warrington and [?], 1923-1930 (Box 2)
    There are three letters in this folder. The first is addressed to Warrington. The other two are addressed to "My dear Young Friend" and the second to "My dear Sir." They both refer to Francis W. Dawson and his wife, but they refer to them as the addressee's Grand-Father and Grand-Mother. This would mean they are not addressed to Warrington, who was their son. It's not certain, but more likely, that they were addressed to Stuyvesant Barry, FWD's grandson, who was at Harvard in 1930 and writing his thesis on FWD. He wrote and interviewed everyone he could find. Baynard was a reporter on the News and Courier, and worked for FWD for years, as he describes in the letters.
  - Baynard, J. S. to various, 1888 (Box 2)
  - Bayard, Herbert to Dawson, Warrington, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Bazin, René to [?], 1931 (Box 2)
  - Beach, Julia to Morgan, Sarah, 1889 (Box 2)
  - Beacham, W. L. to [?], 1888 (Box 2)
  - Beaman, Ida to Dawson, Warrington, 1913 (Box 2)
  - Beard, C. H. to Dawson, F. W., 1888 (Box 2)
  - Beaumont, G. de to [?], 1931-1933 (Box 2)
  - Beauregard, Thibault de to Dawson, Warrington, 1933 (Box 2)
  - Beaureguard, A. T. to Dawson, Warrington, 1934-1935 (Box 2)
  - Beekman, Frederick to Dawson, Warrington and [?], 1934-1935 (Box 2)
  - Beer, Rona to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 and undated (Box 2)
  - Begnard, Lucien to Dawson, Warrington, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
  - Begnier, B. to Dawson, Warrington and [?], 1912-1913 (Box 2)
  - Beichignac, P. Vincent to [?], 1931 (Box 2)
  - Bein, Lucien to Dawson, Warrington, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Bell, George to Dawson, F. W., 1887 (Box 2)
  - Bell, Jean to Dawson, Warrington, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Bell, Laura to Dawson, Warrington, 1913 (Box 2)
  - Bell, Nannie to Drum, Lavinia (Morgan), 1889 (Box 2)
  - Bellet, Henry du to Grefuhle, 1908 (Box 2)
  - Bellinger, G. Duncan to Tyghe, 1888 (Box 2)
  - Bellinger, J. B. to Morgan, Sarah, 1889 (Box 2)
  - Bellinger, John to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Bellinger, Mary to Morgan, Sarah, 1889 (Box 2)
  - Bellinger, W. W. to Morgan, Sarah, 1889 (Box 2)
  - Bemhardt, Sarah to Dawson, Warrington, 1907 (Box 2)
  - Benet, Christine to Dawson, Warrington, 1918 (Box 2)
  - Benet, Margaret Cox to Dawson, Warrington, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Benet, W. C. to Morgan, Sarah, 1889 (Box 2)
  - Benton, Phylis to Dawson, Warrington, 1931-1933 (Box 2)
  - Benvenisti, Odette to various, 1918-1919 (Box 2)
  - Bernard, Bernard to Dawson, Warrington, 1929-1930 (Box 2)
  - Bernard, Mary to Dawson, Warrington, 1926 (Box 2)
  - Bernard, W. H. to [?], 1888 (Box 2)
  - Berry, Thomas to Dawson, F. W., 1888 (Box 2)
  - Berry, Walter to various, 1922-1927 (Box 2)
    This includes two letters from Berry to Warrington Dawson. The third letter is to "Chere Madame" and it describes something Berry and the Ambassador are trying to do for her "oeuvre," which involves 500 francs. Then it gives charming thanks for an exquisite Ste. Therese and goes on to offer some intimate, friendly comments about vacation, the South, and fresh air. It's signed "Yours devotedly, Walter Berry." At the top of the letter it says COPIE and 53, Rue de Varenne. That is Edith Wharton's address, and she and Berry were devoted friends and possibly lovers.
  - Berthelot, Philippe to Dawson, Warrington, 1925 (Box 2)
  - Berton, Claude to Dawson, Warrington, 1921-1931 (Box 2)
  - Bertramo, Louis to Dawson, Warrington, 1912 (Box 2)
  - Besse, William to various, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Besse, William to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Bhumenstock, B. to [?], 1931 (Box 3)
  - Bickham, R. S. to [?], 1889 (Box 3)
  - Bigelow, John to Dawson, F. W., 1886-1888 (Box 3)
  - Bihn, Henri to Dawson, Warrington, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Billy, E. J. to Dawson, Warrington, undated (Box 3)
  - Bingham, Blauche to Dawson, Warrington, 1935 (Box 3)
  - Bingham, Hiram to various, 1931-1932 (Box 3)
  - Bird, William to Dawson, Warrington, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Bissell, W. C. to Dawson, Warrington, 1903 (Box 3)
  - Bixby, W. H. to various, 1887-1888 (Box 3)
  - Blackford, L. M. to Dawson, F. W., 1889 (Box 3)
  - Blackman, J. K. to Morgan, Sarah, 1891 (Box 3)
  - Blackwell, R. E. to Dawson, Warrington, 1913 (Box 3)
  - Blauche, [?] to Dawson, Warrington, 1919 (Box 3)
  - Blaze, William to [?], 1935 (Box 3)
  - Bloc, M. to [?], 1930 (Box 3)
  - Bloch-Laroque, [?] to [?], 1926-1958 and undated (Box 3)
  - Bloom, Sol to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Blouet, Paul to [?], 1889 (Box 3)
  - Blue, J. G. to Dawson, F. W., 1887 (Box 3)
  - Boatwright, Louise to McKinlay, 1889 (Box 3)
  - Bohlen, Charles to Dawson, Warrington, 1935 (Box 3)
  - Bok, William to Dawson, F. W., 1888-1889 (Box 3)
  - Bolger, H. L. to Morgan, Sarah, 1898 (Box 3)
  - Bolling, Parke to Dawson, Warrington, 1932 and undated (Box 3)
  - Bonbright, James to Dawson, Warrington, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Boneges, Louis to [?], 1931 (Box 3)
  - Bonham, Milledge to Dawson, Warrington, 1930-1932 (Box 3)
  - Bonham, M. L. to Dawson, F. W., 1888 (Box 3)
  - Bonhot, E. to [?], 1938 (Box 3)
  - Bonnet, H. to [?], 1935 (Box 3)
  - Bonnette, P. to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Bond, O. J. to Dawson, Warrington, 1928 (Box 3)
  - Bonney, M. Thérèse to Dawson, Warrington, 1926-1930 (Box 3)
  - Boozer, Albert to Dawson, F. W., 1888-1889 (Box 3)
  - Bordeau, Louis to Drouot, M., 1947 (Box 3)
  - Bosworth, Welles to various, 1928 (Box 3)
  - Bosworth, Welles to Dawson, Warrington, 1931-1935 (Box 3)
  - Botte, Paul to Dawson, Warrington, 1932-1938 (Box 3)
  - Bouillon, Albert to [?], 1932 (Box 3)
  - Boupuereau, Elizabeth to Dawson, Warrington, 1912 (Box 3)
  - Bourdel, Maurice to Dawson, Warrington, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Bourdier, F. to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Bouvet, Maurice to Dawson, Warrington, 1931-1958 and undated (Box 3)
  - Bowan, Paul to Dawson, F. W., 1887 (Box 3)
  - Bowker, R. R. to Dawson, F. W., 1887 (Box 3)
  - Bowles, [?] to Morgan, Sarah, 1889 (Box 3)
  - Byrnes, James to Dawson, Warrington, 1923 (Box 3)
  - Bracey, Annie to Dawson, F. W., undated (Box 3)
  - Brackenbraugh, Betty to Dawson, Warrington, 1910 (Box 3)
  - Brady, Leslie to Dawson, Warrington, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Brantly, William to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Brédif, Henri to Dawson, Warrington, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Brémond, Lucie to [?], 1931 (Box 3)
  - Brennan, E. J. to Dawson, Warrington, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Brentano, P. to Sharp, George, 1928 (Box 3)
  - Brentano, P. to Dawson, Warrington, 1929-1932 (Box 3)
  - Brewster, Anne to Dawson, F. W., 1883 (Box 3)
  - Bridgeman, Amy to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Bright, Mary Eve to Dawson, Warrington, 1933-1935 (Box 3)
  - Brinble, Marjorie to Dawson, Warrington, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Brisson, Pierre to Dawson, Warrington, 1931 and undated (Box 3)
  - Britton, H. to Dawson, Warrington, 1909 (Box 3)
  - Brock, J. A. to Dawson, F. W., 1887 (Box 3)
  - Brodes, Pauline de to various, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Broglie, [?] to [?], 1939 and undated (Box 3)
  - Bronchain, Joseph to [?], 1932 (Box 3)
  - Bronson, A. H. to Dawson, F. W., 1888 (Box 3)
  - Brooke, E. to Dawson, Warrington, 1919 (Box 3)
  - Brower, Henry to Dawson, Warrington, 1926-1927 (Box 3)
  - Brown, C. F. to Dawson, Warrington, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Brown, Joseph to Dawson, Warrington, 1937 (Box 3)
  - Brown, Valentine to [?], undated (Box 3)
  - Browne, H. B. to Morgan, Sarah, 1889 (Box 3)